Guide to the Paul Cooper papers, 1943-1995 MS 463
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Compositions (scores and recordings), 1943-1993
  - Subseries C: Recordings, 1963-1993
    - Sub-subseries 1: Orchestra
      - Variants for Orchestra, York Community High School Orchestra, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 39)
      - Variants for Orchestra (1978), Kern Philharmonic, John Ferrer, conductor, 2/24/1980 (Box 24, Tape 3)
      - Violin Concerto No 1, Ann Arbor Philharmonic, University of Michigan, Rosseels/Aleantara, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 34)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), L'Orchestre Philharmonique de Monte Carlo, Lawrence Foster, conductor, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 26)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), L'Orchestre Philharmonique de Monte Carlo, Patterson/Foster, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 34)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 35)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Kenneth Goldsmith, violin; Giselle Ben-Dor, conductor, 6/28/1988 (Box 24, Tape 36)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), Radio Monte Carlo tape, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 38)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), L'Orchestre Philharmonique de Monte Carlo, Patterson, violin, Foster, conductor, 4/17/1983 (Box 30, Tape 31)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (1980-82), L'orchestre Philharmonique de Monte Carlo, Patterson, violin, Foster, conductor, 4/17/1983 (Box 33, Tape 25)
      - Violin Concerto No 2 (defective tape), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 37)
      - Works by Dufay, Anheim, Cooper (Symphony No 2?), Bruch, Bartok, Shepherd Symphony Orchestra and Choir, 10/5/1991 (Box 25, Tape 7)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Chamber
      - Canonic variations (first performance), University of Michigan Woodwind Quintet, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 27)
      - Canonic variations (rehearsal), n.d. (Box 32, Tape 23)
      - Canons d'amour (1981), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 12)
      - Canons d'amour (1981), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 13)
      - Canons D'amour (1981), Duo Patterson, Recording project, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 39)
      - Canons D'amour (1981), Duo Patterson, 6/24-6/25/1994, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 41)
      - Canons D'amour (1981), Duo Patterson, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 42)
      - Canons D'amour, SIDE B, Shepherd Quartet, 2/3/1995 (Box 26, Tape 12)
      - Canons D'amour, SIDE B, Shepherd Quartet, 12/19/1994 (Box 26, Tape 13)
      - Canti, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 7)
      - Canti, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 10)
      - Canti (1981), NYC Premiere, Crouse, Gates, 5/26/1987 (Box 27, Tape 1)
      - Canti for viola and piano (world premiere), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano,, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 4/8/1981 (Box 31, Tape 8)
      - Canti for viola and piano (world premiere), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Concert: "The 20th Century Violinist", 4/8/1981 (Box 33, Tape 8)
      - Canti for viola and piano (world premiere), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Concert: "The 20th Century Violinist", 4/8/1981 (Box 33, Tape 9)
      - Canti for viola and pianoforte [Composer's note: Defective tape, bad hum and quits], n.d. (Box 27, Tape 2)
      - Canzona, Shepherd School Brass Ensemble, Stude Hall, Rice University, 1/31/1994 (Box 27, Tape 7)
      - Chamber music, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 4)
      - Chamber Music I (1982), n.d. (Box 31, Tape 9)
      - Chamber Music II (1983), n.d. (Box 31, Tape 10)
      - Chamber Music II (1983), world premiere, for flute, two clarinets, violin, cello, and piano, Caruth Auditorium, SMU, Voices of Change, Texas Premieres, 2/28/1983 (Box 31, Tape 21)
      - Chimera (1973), Lorna Larson, violin, Marilyn Emmons, Viola, John Parsons, Cello, Robert Ellis, Piano, Colorado State University, Dept of Music, Music Building, Concert Hall, A recital of Compositions by Paul Cooper, 4/7/1975 (Box 31, Tape 11)
      - Concert for Three (1977), Angeneam Trio, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 8)
      - Concert for Three, for clarinet, cello, piano, Ross Powell, clarinet; Craig Weaver, Cello, unknown pianist, Caruth Auditorium, SMU, Voices of Change, Texas Premieres, The Sixth Season, "Taste of Texas", 3/9/1981 (Box 31, Tape 7)
      - Concert for Three, for clarinet, cello, piano, Ross Powell, clarinet; Craig Weaver, Cello, unknown pianist, Caruth Auditorium, SMU, Voices of Change, Texas Premieres, The Sixth Season, "Taste of Texas", 3/9/1981 (Box 33, Tape 6)
      - Concert for Two (1966), Jerome Jelinek, cello, Rhea Kish, piano, 1/29/1967 (Box 33, Tape 19)
      - Cooper Quartet, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 18)
      - Cooper series, tape one: French Horn and Piano, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 30)
      - Descants (1975), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 17)
      - Descants (Side A), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 18)
      - Dialogues (1994), World Premiere, The Swedish Radio Symphony Orchestra, Ola Karlsson, cello; Leif Segerstam, conductor, The Berwald Hall, Stockholm, 10/27/1995 (Box 27, Tape 14)
      - Doctoral work recital, Viola Sonata, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 21)
      - Elegies, Desmond Hoebig, Brian Connelly, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 5)
      - Elegies, Desmond Hoebig, Brian Connelly, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 6)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 19)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992, Fischer Duo, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/2/1994 (Box 27, Tape 20)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992, Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 27, Tape 21)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), n.d. (Box 28, Tape 10)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 28, Tape 11)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 28, Tape 12)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 28, Tape 13)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 28, Tape 14)
      - Elegies for cello and piano (1992), Desmond Hoebig, cello, Brian Connelly, piano, Texas Duos, 3/3/1992 (Box 28, Tape 15)
      - Epitaphs, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 18)
      - Fanfare for Brass quintet (Composers note: error in recording), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 6)
      - Flute sonata, excerpts, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 25)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 26)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 27)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), Laura Hunter, saxophone, Brian Connelly, piano, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 28)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), D. Hastings, Saxophone, C.Kefferstan, piano, Faculty recital, 3/10/1992 (Box 27, Tape 29)
      - Four Impromptus for alto saxophone and piano (1983), D. Hastings, Saxophone, C.Kefferstan, piano, WVMTNA Clinic, 6/15/1992 (Box 27, Tape 29)
      - Four Impromptus for Alto Saxophone and piano (1983), Duo Vivo, Laura Hunter, saxophone, Brian Connelly, piano, Syzygy Concert, 10/30/1984 (Box 30, Tape 32)
      - Intimate voices, Florida Arts Trio, in University Memorial Auditorium, Janna Lower, violin, Mark Tanner, cello, Kevin Sharpe, Piano, 11/11/1993 (Box 25, Tape 12)
      - Kammarmusik by Paul Cooper, Produced by Radiohuset, Studio 2, Musikhogskolan I Stockholm, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 27)
      - Paul Cooper: Kammermusik, Stockholm, RadioHuset, Studio 2, Musikhogskolan, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 8)
      - Piano Quintet (1994), Premiere, The Cuerteto Latinoamericano, John Perry, piano, 9/28/1995 (Box 25, Tape 19)
      - Piano Quintet (1994), Premiere, The Cuerteto Latinoamericano, John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 23)
      - Piano Quintet (note: different title on case), The University of Florida, Society of Composers, Inc. Region IV Conference, 11/10-11/13/1993, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 17)
      - Piano Quintet (Premiere), The Cuerteto Latinoamericano, John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 24)
      - Piano Quintet (Premiere), The Cuerteto Latinoamericano, John Perry, piano, Stude Concert Hall, Rice University, 9/28/1995 (Box 25, Tape 25)
      - Piano quintet (three movts), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 6)
      - Quartet No 3, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 20)
      - Quartet No 5 (Umbrae), The Shepherd Quartet, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 28)
      - Quartet No 5 'Umbrae' (1973), premiere, The Shepherd Quartet, Ronald Patterson, Raphael Fliegel, Wayne Crouse, Shirley Trepel, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 28)
      - Quartet No 5, (work tape), n.d. (Box 29, Tape 31)
      - Quartet No 6 "early rehearsal", n.d. (Box 29, Tape 36)
      - Quartet No 6 (1977), The Shepherd Quartet, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY: Retrospective: Chamber Music of Paul Cooper., 11/30/1978 (Box 29, Tape 21)
      - Quartet No. 2, USC Retro, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 17)
      - Quartet No. 3 (1959), The Stanley Quartet, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 20)
      - Requiem for organ and percussion (1978), Raver/Brown, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 17)
      - Requiem for organ and percussion (1978), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 30)
      - Requiem for organ and percussion (Side B), Raver/Brown, Stude Concert Hall, Rice University, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 18)
      - Rondels Bergamasques (1988), The New York New Music Ensemble, Christine Schadeberg, soprano, 11/5/1989 (Box 26, Tape 15)
      - Serenade, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 5)
      - Serenade for six players, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 41)
      - Serenade for six players, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 42)
      - Sinfonia for winds, University of Maryland Band, Acton Ostling, conductor, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 23)
      - Soliloquies (1970), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 3)
      - Soliloquies (1970) for violin and piano, 8/1/1974 (Box 32, Tape 3)
      - Soliloquies for violin and piano (1970), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 6)
      - Soliloquies for Violin and Piano (1970), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 37)
      - Soliloquies for violin and piano (1972), Ronald Patterson, violin, Anne Schnoebelen, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY: Retrospective: Chamber Music of Paul Cooper., 11/30/1978 (Box 29, Tape 21)
      - Sonata a Tre, The Shepherd Quartet, Ronald Patterson, violin, Raphael Fliefel, Violin, Wayne Crouse, Viola, Shirley Trepel, cello, 9/21/1975 (Box 29, Tape 13)
      - Sonata for Bass and Piano (1964), Lawrence Hurst, bass, Robert Jones, pianist, (copied from a School of Music Master Tape, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 32)
      - Sonata for Cello and Piano (1963), Carolyn Tolson, cello, David Yeomans, piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 15)
      - Sonata for Cello and Piano, No. 1 (1963), Oliver Edel, Barbara Holmquist, 4/23/1964 (Box 32, Tape 22)
      - Sonata for Flute and piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 19)
      - Sonata for Flutes (1963), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 16)
      - Sonata for Flutes and Piano (1963), Susanne Oldham, Flute, Bruce Gibbons, Piano, Colorado State University, Dept of Music, Music Building, Concert Hall, A recital of Compositions by Paul Cooper, 4/7/1975 (Box 31, Tape 11)
      - Sonata for Violin and Piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 37)
      - Sonata for Violin and Piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 42)
      - Sonata, Cello and piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 25)
      - String Quartet No 1 (1953), The Shepherd Quartet, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY Retrospective Concert: Music of Paul Cooper, 11/30/1978 (Box 32, Tape 10)
      - String Quartet No 1, 1953, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 3, 1959, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 4, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 36)
      - String Quartet No 4 (1964), West Point String Quartet, Performed at School of Music Recital Hall, Greenville, N.C. 27834, East Carolina University Festival, 1970, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 15)
      - String Quartet No 4 (1964), United States Military Academy Band letter, 8/12/1969 (Box 32, Tape 35)
      - String Quartet No 4, 1964, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 11)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 35)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 26)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 3)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 4)
      - String Quartet No 5, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 32)
      - String Quartet No 5 (Umbrae), The Shepherd Quartet, Ronald Patterson, violin, Raphael Fliegel, violin, Wayne Crouse, viola, Shirley Trepel, cello, 9/21/1975 (Box 29, Tape 14)
      - String Quartet No 5, 'Umbrae', (1973), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 6, N.B. Includes performance notes by the composer, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 5)
      - String Quartet No 6, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 8)
      - String Quartet No 6, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 9)
      - String Quartet No 6 (1977), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - String Quartet No 6 (1977), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 12)
      - String quartet No 6 (1977), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 13)
      - String Quartet No 6 (1977), KLEF Broadcast, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 20)
      - String Quartet No 6 (1977), 11/10 - 11/13/1993 (Box 25, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 6 (1977), Society of Composers, Region IV Conference, The University of Florida, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 22)
      - String Quartet No 6 (premiere), n.d. (Box 29, Tape 10)
      - String Quartet No 6 (premiere), The Shepherd Quartet, Ronald Patterson, violin, Raphael Fliefel, Violin, Wayne Crouse, Viola, Shirley Trepel, cello, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Recorded by John Profit, radio KLEF, Houston, 1/25/1978 (Box 33, Tape 5)
      - String Quartet No 6, 1978, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 21)
      - String Quartet No 6, SIDE B, Shepherd Quartet, 2/3/1995 (Box 26, Tape 12)
      - String Quartet No 6, SIDE B, Shepherd Quartet, 12/19/1994 (Box 26, Tape 13)
      - String Quartet No. 6, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 1)
      - String Quartet No.6 (coda), n.d. (Box 26, Tape 19)
      - Tre Voci (violin, violoncello, piano (1987), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 12)
      - Tre Voci (violin, violoncello, piano (1987), The University of Florida, Society of Composer, Inc. Region IV Conference, 11/10-11/13/1993 (Box 26, Tape 6)
      - Tre Voci (violin, violoncello, piano (1987), The University of Florida, Society of Composer, Inc. Region IV Conference, 11/10-11/13/1993 (Box 26, Tape 10)
      - Tre Voci (violin, violoncello, piano (1987), n.d. (Box 26, Tape 11)
      - Tre Voci (violin, violoncello, piano (1987), n.d. (Box 28, Tape 10)
      - Umbrae (String Quartet #5), SIDE A, Shepherd Quartet, 2/3/1995 (Box 26, Tape 12)
      - Umbrae (String Quartet #5), SIDE A, Shepherd Quartet, 12/19/1994 (Box 26, Tape 13)
      - Umbrae (String Quartet No 5), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 12)
      - Umbrae (String Quartet No 5), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 13)
      - Variants for Viola and Piano (1971), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY Retrospective Concert: Music of Paul Cooper, 11/30/1978 (Box 32, Tape 10)
      - Variants for Violin and Piano, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 1)
      - Variants II (1972), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - Variants IV, Rodica Oancea, violin?, Student recital, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 18)
      - Variants IV (1986), 11/7/1986 (Box 24, Tape 2)
      - Variants IV (1986), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 39)
      - Variants IV (1986), Hunter/Connelly, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 40)
      - Variation for violin and piano (1967), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 34)
      - Variations for violin (1967), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 16)
      - Variations for Violin and Piano (1967), Thomas Leveck, violin, Robert Lucas, piano, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 25)
      - Variations for violin and Piano (1967), Thomas LeVeck, violin, Robert Lucas, piano, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 35)
      - Verses pour violon et alto, Shepherd Quartet, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 11)
      - Verses pour violon et alto (1991), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 13)
      - Verses pour violon et alto (1991), Duo Patterson, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 40)
      - Verses pour violon et alto (1991), Duo Patterson, Nice, France, Digital rendezvous, 6/24-6/25/1994, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 41)
      - Verses pour violon et alto (1991), Duo Patterson, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 42)
      - Verses pour violon et alto, SIDE A, Shepherd Quartet, 2/3/1995 (Box 26, Tape 12)
      - Verses pour violon et alto, SIDE A, Shepherd Quartet, 12/19/1994 (Box 26, Tape 13)
      - Viola sonata, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 16)
      - Viola sonata, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 24)
      - Viola sonata (or Sonata for Cello and Piano, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 33)
      - Violin sonata, Rosseels/Berry, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 28)
      - Violin variations (copy of Chamber Music Recital, Tape 2), n.d. (Box 32, Tape 19)
      - Woodwind quartet (two movts), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 6)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Keyboard
      - Alleluias (premiere), Marilyn Keiser, organ, 7/12/1994 (Box 26, Tape 35)
      - Cooper: Sinfonia, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 32)
      - Cycles (1969), Bill Holmquest, piano, Wigmore Hall, 11/6/1970 (Box 27, Tape 13)
      - Cycles (1969), Robert Hammond, piano, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 36)
      - Cycles for Piano (1969), n.d. (Box 33, Tape 23)
      - Four Intermezzi, Gary Smart, piano, 10/12/1981 (Box 30, Tape 26)
      - Frescoes (1994), Duncan Hall, Rice University, Syzygy Concert, 11/2/1995 (Box 27, Tape 31)
      - Improv for Sinfonia, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 27)
      - In Nomine, University of Texas, Austin, 5/28/1985 (Box 27, Tape 32)
      - In Nomine, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 33)
      - In Nomine (1984), Benbow, Central Presbyterian Church, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 39)
      - Partimento, Edward Heenan, piano, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 29)
      - Selection of works by various composers including Paul Cooper's In Nomine, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 36)
      - Sinfonia, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, Syzygy Concert, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 33)
      - Sinfonia, John Hendrickson, piano, Syzygy Concert, 3/30/1993 (Box 26, Tape 34)
      - Sinfonia (1989), John Perry, piano, 4/2/1995 (Box 26, Tape 30)
      - Sinfonia for piano, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 29)
      - Sinfonia for solo piano, 3/5/1992 (Box 26, Tape 31)
      - Sinfonia for solo piano (1989), John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 37)
      - Sinfonia for solo piano (1989), John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 39)
      - Sinfonia for solo piano (1989), John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 40)
      - Sinfonia for solo piano (1989), World Premiere, John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 2)
      - Sinfonia Improvisation by Paul Cooper, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 26)
      - Sinfonia Improvisation No 1, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 25)
      - Sinfornia Improvisation, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 28)
      - Sinfornia Improvisation no.2, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 24)
      - Sonata (1962), Fred Oldenburg, piano, Ysbreuer Amsterdam, 4/16/1989 (Box 26, Tape 23)
      - Sonata for piano (1962), Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY Retrospective Concert: Music of Paul Cooper, 11/30/1978 (Box 32, Tape 10)
      - Three piano sonatas, USC Retro, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 13)
      - Variants for Organ, David Craighead, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 28)
      - Variants for Organ, David Craighead, 6/13/1975 (Box 31, Tape 31)
      - Works by Chopin, Mozart, Cooper, Sugar Hill studio recording, John Perry, piano, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 3)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Vocal/Choral
      - Cantigas (1972), n.d. (Box 31, Tape 23)
      - Cantigas (1972), Choruses and Philharmonic Orchestra of the College-Conservatory of Cincinnatti, Elmer Thomas, conductor, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 10)
      - Cantigas (1972), C.C.M. Orchestra and Choruses, Kathleen Battle, soprano; Elmer Thomas, conductor, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 16)
      - Cantigas (1972), premiere, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 34)
      - Cantigas for Double Chorus and Orchestra, Chorale and Chamber Singers, Concert Orchestra of CCM, Elmer Thomas, conductor, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 29)
      - Cantigas for Double Chorus and Orchestra (1972), Commissioned by James Riley for Ruth Riley, Elmer Thomas Conducting, Kathy Battle, soprano solo, Concert Orchestra and Chamber Singers of the College-Conservatory of Music, University of Cincinatti, University of Cincinnati, Januray, 1973, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 4)
      - Celebration, SATB, organ, celebrant, Trinity Church, Jacksonville, Florida, 4/10/1983 (Box 30, Tape 5)
      - Credo (1970), Choruses and Philharmonic Orchestra of the College-Conservatory of Cincinnatti, Elmer Thomas, conductor, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 10)
      - Credo (1970), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 12)
      - Credo (1970), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 16)
      - Credo for double chorus and orchestra, Text of C.E.Cooper (1970), premiere, The Chamber Choir, Chorale and the Philharmonia Orchestra, Elmer Thomas, conductor, Cincinnati, OH, April, 1971, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 33)
      - Equinox, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 22)
      - Equinox, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 32)
      - Equinox (1976), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 24)
      - Omnia tempus habent (1987), Opening Service of the 1988 AGO Convention, Houston, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 1)
      - Refrains, Chorus and orchestra of Rhode Island College, Providence, Edward Markward, conducting, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 5)
      - Refrains (1976), Rhode Island College Chorus and Orchestra, Edward Markward, conductor, Providence, Rhode Island, 12/6/1976 (Box 30, Tape 27)
      - Refrains for chorus and orchestra, 12/6/1976 (Box 30, Tape 2)
      - Voyagers (1983), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - Voyagers (1983), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 31)
      - Voyagers (1983), KUSC Broadcast, 2/15/1984 (Box 24, Tape 32)
      - Voyagers (1983), Shepherd Symphony Orchestra and Choir, Stude Hall, Shepherd School Concert, 3/22/1996 (Box 24, Tape 33)
      - Voyagers (1983), Shepherd Symphony Orchestra and Choir, 3/22/1996 (Box 25, Tape 13)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Vocal/Solo
      - "Parable for Soprano and Organ", n.d. (Box 25, Tape 6)
      - Coram Morte, Cambiata Soloists, Isabelle Ganz, mezzo-soprano, Ellsworth Milburn, conductor, University of Houston, Clear Lake, 1/28/1979 (Box 32, Tape 1)
      - Coram Morte, Cambiata soloists, Clear Lake, Clear Lake, 1/28/1979 (Box 31, Tape 35)
      - Coram Morte, Cambiata soloists, Clear Lake, 1/28/1979 (Box 31, Tape 36)
      - Coram Morte (1978), Christine Schadeberg, soprano, Dallas, Voice of Change, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 11)
      - Coram Morte (1978), Christina Schadeberg, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 17)
      - Coram Morte (1979), Cambiata soloists, Isabelle Ganz, mezzo-soprano, Arthur Gottschalk, synthesizer, Ellsworth Milburn, conductor, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 1/17/1979 (Box 31, Tape 24)
      - Coram Morte (from Voices of Change), Live broadcast, 3/19/1979 (Box 31, Tape 34)
      - Coran Morte, Voices of Change, Christina Shadeberg, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 3)
      - Four Songs, USC Retro, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 17)
      - From the Sacred Harp, Francis Bible, mezzo-soprano, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 35)
      - From the Sacred Harp (1982), Suzanne Marion, mezzo-soprano, Rochelle Kahan, piano, 1/22/1991 (Box 27, Tape 34)
      - From the Sacred Harp: Come on my friends, The Holy City, The Scriptures are fulfilling, I want to Live, Robert Ames, Baritone, Colleen Gehrich, piano, First Unitarian Universalist Church of Houston, 77th Birthday Gala Concert, 2/9/1991 (Box 24, Tape 29)
      - Impressions (1944), Jeanette Lombard, soprano, John Hendrickson, piano, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 9)
      - Last call (1990), Carolann Page, Da Camera Society, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 7)
      - Last call (1990), Carolann Page, Da Camera Society, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 3)
      - Last call (1990), Rehearsal, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 4)
      - Last call (1990), Carolann Page, Da Camera Society, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 5)
      - Last call (1990), Carolann Page, Da Camera Society, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 6)
      - Last call; Arias and Recitatives on Poems of C.E.Cooper, Carolann Page, soprano, Sergiu Luca, violin, Atar Arad, viola, Brian Connelly, piano, Anthony Ross, cello, Carol Wincenc, fulte, Charles Neidich, clarinet, The Menil Collection, Houston, 10/9/1990 (Box 28, Tape 8)
      - Mirrors (1986), Sonanza of Stockholm, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 10/9/1986 (Box 25, Tape 32)